Guide to the Time Inc. Editorial Services Records 1966-1977, 1991-2003 MS 3009-RG 47
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Editorial Services Records
1966-1977, 1991-2003
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 47
7.92 Linear feet in 7 record cartons and 1 flat box
Editorial Services Records documents the activities of various departments and offices within this division that supported all editorial and publishing divisions at Time Inc. The majority of records are from several photograph syndication services at Time Inc. Also included are office files from the Editorial Production/Copy Processing department and photographs of staff events.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include contracts with Time Inc. or any of its subsidiaries as a party; and personnel files including performance reviews or personally identifiable information. Restricted materials are located in box R62.
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Arrangement
Organized into three series:
Series I. Syndication Records
Series II. Editorial Production / Copy Processing Records
Series III. Staff Events Photographic Material
Historical Note
Editorial Services was established as a central corporate division in 1967 with four departments: Bureau of Editorial Services; Editorial Production; the Photo Lab; and the Picture Collection. These departments supported the research, editorial, and publishing efforts of the Time Inc. magazines. Departments and offices within Editorial Services reorganized frequently.
Bureau of Editorial Services, transferred from the Time Editorial Department in 1967, was sometimes known as the "Word Morgue". In 1971, it was renamed the Library.
Editorial Production transferred from the Time Editorial Department in 1967 and contained the Photon and Copy Processing operations. In 1970 Editorial Production ceased Photon operations and became synonymous with Copy Processing. In 1981 Editorial Production/Copy Processing detached from Editorial Services and transferred to separate management.
The Photo Lab transferred from the Life Editorial Department in 1967 and remained a department until Editorial Services closed in 2001.
The Picture Collection transferred from the Life Editorial Department in 1967. While at Life, it was known as the Picture Morgue then the Life Picture Collection.
Prior to closing, Life magazine operated the Time-Life Syndication Service. After Life ceased operations, Editorial Services established the Time-Life Picture Agency, also known as the Time-Life Picture Service, within the Picture Collection to take over syndication services.
Other syndication offices within Editorial Services included the Life Picture Service, Time & Life Syndication and TimePix. Time & Life Syndication transferred to Editorial Services around 1994 and may have been an office created by the reorganization of Life Picture Service and Time Pix Syndication (a Time editorial division) in the late 1980s or early 1990s. Time Inc. established TimePix around 1999 replacing Time & Life Syndication.
History of Offices in the Editorial Services Division
1967 September Editorial Services is established.
1970 January Editorial Production ceases Photon operations. From this point the Editorial Production department becomes synonymous with Copy Processing.
1971 April Bureau of Editorial Reference is renamed the Library.
1973 Time-Life Picture Agency is established under the Picture Collection.
1976 December Time-Life Picture Agency closes. Editorial Services continues to provide syndication services.
1978 First mention of the Life Picture Service which replaces the Time-Life Picture Agency.
1981 May Editorial Production/Copy Processing detaches from Editorial Services to separate management.
1982 January Life Picture Service transfers to new Life magazine.
circa 1994 Time & Life Syndication transfers to Editorial Services. The Archives transfers to Editorial Services.
1996 The Library and the Archives are reorganized and renamed Time Research Center.
circa 1999 TimePix established.
2001 August Time Research Center is decentralized from Editorial Services and dissolved.
2001 November The Photo Lab, Picture Collection and TimePix are decentralized and downsized and the Editorial Services division closes.
2003 April TimePix is sold to Getty Images.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library. Records on the history of Editorial Services, or on services provided by them such as syndication, are located in Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1).
Scope and Contents
Editorial Services Records documents the activities of various departments and offices within this division. The majority of records are from several photograph syndication services at Time Inc. Also included are office files from the Editorial Production/Copy Processing department and photographs of staff events.
Color negatives.; Color photographs.; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files; Periodicals -- Publishing.; Photographers' representatives; Photographers -- United States; Printing industry -- New York (State) -- New York.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I. Syndication Records, 1966-1974, 1991-2003; 5 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
  Historical Note
  Time-Life Picture Agency, Time & Life Syndication, and TimePix were all offices within Editorial Services that handled the syndication or right of reproduction of Time Inc. magazine content. These responsibilities were passed between Editorial Services and Life magazine since the majority of material requested was photographs from Life, and syndication offices frequently were established, replaced, and dissolved.
  - Subseries I.A. Commission Cards, 1966-1971; 2.75 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    Scope and Contents
    A commission card can be used for writers, artists or photographers. The commission cards in this collection primarily represent photographers. Individual photographer cards track purchases by other publications or companies of the photographer's Time Inc. work including who purchased it, what was purchased, the commission amount, and the amount earned by Time Inc. Control cards for each type of photographer are also included that seem to track totals for each category by week, month or country. The cards predate any syndication office within Editorial Services and probably were inhertied from the syndication offices originally at Life magazine.
    Arrangement
    Organized by year with type of photographer groups arranged alphabetically within each year based on the original order. The materials were not originally in folders, but were grouped by year and photographer type.
    - Contract, 1966 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 1)
    - Freelance, 1966 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 2)
    - No Credit, 1966 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 3)
    - Photographer Unknown, 1966 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 4)
    - Staff, 1966 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 5)
    - Billings, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 6)
    - By Month/By Country, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 7)
    - Contract, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 8)
    - Freelance, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 9)
    - No Credit, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 10-15)
    - Service Charges, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 16)
    - Staff, 1967 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 17)
    - Billings, 1968 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 18)
    - By Country/By Month, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 19)
    - By Month, 1968 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 20-21)
    - Contract, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 22-24)
    - Freelance, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 25)
    - New York City Sales Tax, 1968 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 26)
    - No Credit, 1968 (Offsite-box 3842, Folder 27-29)
    - No Credit, 1968 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 1-4)
    - Service Charges, 1968 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 5)
    - Staff, 1968 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 6)
    - By Country/By Month, 1969 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 7)
    - By Month, 1969 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 8)
    - Country: Gross Sales, 1969 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 9)
    - Contract, 1969 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 10)
    - Freelance, 1969 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 11)
    - No Credit, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3843, Folder 12-16)
    - Staff, 1969 (Offsite-box 3844, Folder 1)
    - By Country, 1971 (Offsite-box 3844, Folder 2)
    - By Country/By Month, 1971 (Offsite-box 3844, Folder 3)
    - Freelance, 1971 (Offsite-box 3844, Folder 4-8)
    - No Credit, 1971 (Offsite-box 3844, Folder 9)
    - Staff, 1971 (Offsite-box 3844, Folder 10-13)
  - Subseries I.B. Time-Life Syndication Service / Time-Life Picture Agency Files, 1972-1974; 1.6 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Time-Life Syndication Service / Time-Life Picture Agency Files contain materials that originated with the syndication department within Life and transferred to Editorial Services. Records include order confirmations, invoices, and correspondence for the use of images printed in Time Inc. publications, primarily Life. Requests for syndication usually come from publishing companies.
    The records are water damaged causing some papers to adhere together decreasing usability.
    Organized alphabetically by requestor name based on the original arrangement. The "B" folders are not present.
    - A-M, 1972-1974 (Offsite-box 3845, Folder 1-18)
    - N-XYZ, 1972-1974 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 1-15)
  - Subseries I.C. Time & Life Syndication Files, 1991-2000; 0.25 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
    Time & Life Syndication contains files from this version of the syndication office within Editorial Services. Records include correspondence to and from Director Maryann Kornely regarding syndication agreements and files from her previous position with Life Picture Sales; memoranda from Uri Davidov with syndication reports; and syndication policies.
    Organized alphabetically. Arrangement imposed.
    - Foreign Rights, 1991, 1999 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 16)
    - Foreign Rights [RESTRICTED], 1991, 2000 (Offsite-box R62)
    - Fortune Syndication, 1998-2000 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 17)
    - Fortune Syndication [RESTRICTED], 1999-2000 (Offsite-box R62)
    - Fortune Syndication Sales Summary, 1998-1999 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 18)
    - Life Picture Sales: Graphique de France, 1990-1995 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 19)
    - Life Picture Sales: Graphique de France [RESTRICTED], 1990-1992 (Offsite-box R62)
  - Subseries I.D. TimePix Files, 1991-2003; 0.25 Linear feet in 4 folders
    The TimePix Files contain records from this version of the syndication office within Editorial Services. Records include price guides, promotional materials and realia, lists of photographers in the collection along with notes on their sales and rights; and correspondence.
    - Price Guide, 2002 May 13 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 20)
    - Promotional Material, 2003 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 21-22)
    - Representation Lists, 1991, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 23)
    - TIHE-Hasbro LIFE GI Joe, 2001 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 24)
- Series II. Editorial Production / Copy Processing Records, 1967-1977; 1.05 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Contains records from Operations Manager Ken Shaw and Editorial Production manager Mike Keene. The records primarily come from Shaw.
  Records include memoranda to department staff, correspondence with other divisions within Time Inc., notes, personnel and employee files, and guides and manuals for editorial production operations.
  Organized alphabetically with a folder of miscellaneous material at the end. Arrangement imposed.
  - Airey, Norman, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 1)
  - Bachman, Harriet / Time Copy Desk, 1970-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 2)
  - Barr, Donald, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 3)
  - Copy Processing Procedures, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 4)
  - Copy Processing System, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 5)
  - Dauler, John, 1972-1975 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 6)
  - Demeter, Steve, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 7)
  - Department Head Directory, 1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 8)
  - Direct Transmission System Operating Guide, 1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 9)
  - Forms, circa 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 10)
  - Fortune Memoranda, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 11)
  - FYI, 1967 August 11 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 12)
  - Grunwald, Henry, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 13)
  - Holidays, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 14)
  - Home Box Office (HBO), 1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 15)
  - Jamieson, Edward, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 16)
  - Keene, Mike, 1972-1977 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 17-18)
  - Memoranda: General, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 19)
  - Memoranda: Shaw, Ken, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 20)
  - Money, 1972-1975 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Guild of New York, 1967-1974 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Guild of New York [RESTRICTED], 1972 (Offsite-box R62)
  - Overtime Summary, 1971-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 23)
  - Pappas, Carolyn / Payroll, 1973-1975 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 24)
  - People, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 25)
  - Performance Appraisals [RESTRICTED] (3 folders), 1972-1974 (Offsite-box R62)
  - Personnel Files, 1969-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 26)
  - Personnel Files [RESTRICTED], 1970-1976 (Offsite-box R62)
  - Petty Cash Lists, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 27)
  - Puccia, Ed, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 28)
  - Riggio, Suzanne, 1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 29)
  - Sports Illustrated, 1969-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 30)
  - Suggestions, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 31)
  - Typefaces, 1976 January (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 32)
  - Vacations, 1974-1976 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 33)
  - Wagner, Jim, 1963-1964, 1972 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972, 1977 (Offsite-box 3847, Folder 35)
- Series III. Staff Events Photographic Material, 1996-circa 1999; 1.667 Linear feet in 1 flat box and 2 folders
  Photograph albums and negatives document Editorial Services staff outings and events. The albums depict a party on a boat. The negatives depict various events including the Time Research Center opening and Glenn Laflin's farewell party along with unidentified events.
  - Photograph album: General, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 3848, Item 1)
  - Photograph album: General, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 3848, Item 2)
  - Photograph album: Photos by Martha Holmes, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 3848, Item 3)
  - Photograph album: Property of Rodriguez, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 3848, Item 4)
  - Photograph negatives, 1996-circa 1999 (Offsite-box 3846, Folder 26-27)